Paul Mowat

E: paul@paulmowat.co.uk, W: http://www.paulmowat.co.uk

Summary

I am a hardworking, organized and motivated software developer with 10+ years experience designing and supporting large scale applications on a variety of platforms and technologies including Progress OpenEdge, C#, SQL Server and Java.

My experience also extends to web development using HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP and hybrid mobile applications.

I have strong problem solving skills and am an advocate of best practices and coding standards.

I enjoy working within a team and have experience leading teams of developers using traditional and agile methodologies to meet tight deadlines.

During my spare time, I also seek to continually improve my skills and knowledge and as such I enjoy learning about new emerging technologies. I am currently increasing my knowledge of Node.js and Angular 2 as I see this as a key technology of the future.

My other interests include photography, watching movies and spending time with my wife and son.

Technical Skills

General	Applications	Microsoft Office, Beyond Compare
	Operating Systems	Windows, Linux, Unix and Mac OSX
Web Development	Languages/ Frameworks	HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, PHP, SQL, XML, XSLT, AngularJS, Bootstrap, ASP.NET, Gulp, NodeJS, REST/SOAP Webservices
	Applications	Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Visual Studio Code
Application Development	Languages/ Frameworks	Progress OpenEdge 4GL, C#, Java, Office VBA, Aspose (Word & PDF), SQL, T-SQL
·	Applications	Eclipse, Visual Studio Professional, Progress Developer Studio, Roundtable, Subversion, TortoiseSVN, Github, SourceTree, Installshield, JIRA, Confluence, Jenkins, Octopus Deploy
	Databases	Progress 4GL Database, MYSQL, SQL Server, PostgresSQL, MongoDB

Employment History

Principal Software Developer - November 2012 to Present Senior Software Developer - November 2010 to November 2012

Advanced (Aberdeen, Scotland)

- Assisting with specifications and coding of new modules on an award-winning payroll system used to pay thousands of people around the UK. This needs to be strictly compliant with HMRC rules and regulations.
- Leading Projects with a team of 12 developers to ensure all functionality is delivered as specified, on time and to a high quality. Including managing work outsourced to India.
- Mentoring graduates and other team members who are located both in-house and overseas.
- Database design and implementation on several different database technologies i.e. Progress 4GL and MS SQL.

- Lead in key technical related issues. This includes managing development, build and release environments for the entire team. This was achieved using technologies such as subversion/githib, ant, jenkins, octopus deploy. Including release deployment was done using Installshield.
- Helping improve and implement better overall processes. i.e. Development workflows and Agile development methodologies (Scrum).
- Analysing maintenance issues and providing a quick and efficient turnaround based on customer expectation. Including customer escalations as required and performance tuning.
- Research & Development on new functionality/features/technologies including hybrid mobile development.
- Part of the company software architecture team. Involved in deciding how the company moves forward from a technology and architecture point of view.
- General Application and Hardware support.

Software Engineer - May 2009 to November 2010

Achilles Information Ltd (FPAL) (Aberdeen, Scotland)

- Creating specifications and coding new modules to change websites used by thousands of Oil & Gas customers around the world.
- Tracking down and fixing faults in application and database logic.
- Lead developer on several applications, which required a great deal of workload management to ensure that everything is done within the required deadlines.
- Writing strict standards compliant code in several different languages to match company development and quality assurance policies.
- Part of the company standards team which is used to implement better development standards and software quality processes.
- General Application and Hardware support.

Programmer - June 2006 to May 2009

Trapeze Group (Formally Grampian Software) (Aberdeen, Scotland)

- Maintain and modify programs; make approved changes, develop detailed programming logic, and perform coding changes as per specifications
- Create specifications based on customer's required business logic
- Creating and updating documentation to reflect application changes
- Investigate, Establish and Resolve faults in application logic
- Managing workload and meeting strict deadlines
- Database administration and management
- General application/desktop support for internal staff

Robert Gordon University (Aberdeen, Scotland) - September 2005 to May 2006

Residence Assistant, Woolmanhill Halls

Tesco (Fraserburgh, Scotland) - June 2002 to September 2005

Part Time General Assistant

Gray & Adams (Fraserburgh, Scotland) - June 1998 to June 2001

Welder/Fabricator

Education

Robert Gordon University (Aberdeen, Scotland) - September 2004 to May 2006

BSc (Hons) Computing for Internet & Multimedia – 2:1

Banff and Buchan College (Fraserburgh, Scotland) - August 2002 to May 2004

• HND Software Development - A

Banff and Buchan College (Fraserburgh, Scotland) - August 2001 to May 2002

• SGA Computing & Information Systems (Intermediate 2) – A

Additional

- Good written and verbal communication
- Full Clean Driving License
- Gaining distinction and highest academic achievement in Year 3 of BSc (Hons) Computing for Internet & Multimedia.

References

Available upon request.